Bienen, Leigh B.; Papers apap312
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records, 1908, 1973-1996, Undated; 1; 6.8 cubic ft.
  - Robert Marshall Clipping, 1991 April 12 (Box 3 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 16)
  - Motion to Postpone Briefing and Argument on Proportionality Review or For Extension of Time to File Brief, 1991 April 12 (Box 3 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 17)
  - Encoded Cases - Douglas Mills, Job number 4919, bin D31 [1 of 3], 1991 April 17 (Box 3 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 18)
  - Encoded Cases - Douglas Mills, Job number 4919, bin D31 [2 of 3], 1991 April 17 (Box 3 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 19)
  - Encoded Cases - Douglas Mills, Job number 4919, bin D31 [3 of 3], 1991 April 17 (Box 3 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 20)
  - Baldus Report Clipping, 1991 April 18 (Box 3 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 21)
  - Handwritten Notes on New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall Concerning Methodology of Proportionality Review, 1991 April 23 (Box 3 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 22)
  - Memo on Baldus's First and Second Interim Reports on the Proportionality Review Project, from the Penn Team - with handwritten notes, 1991 April 23 (Box 3 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 23)
  - The Penn Team - Memo on Baldus's First and Second Interim Reports on the Proportionality Review Project, 1991 April 23 (Box 3 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 24)
  - 20th Wave of Progress Reports - List of Cases with Project Status Clearly in, 1991 May 3 (Box 3 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 25)
  - 21st Wave of Progress Reports - List of Cases with Project Status Clearly in, 1991 May 3 (Box 3 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 26)
  - Death Penalty Proportionality Review - Minutes, 1991 May 16 (Box 3 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 27)
  - Meeting Minutes - Annotated Copy (no annotations), 1991 May 16 (Box 3 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 28)
  - Preliminary Outline of Proportionality Brief - with handwritten notes, ca. 1991 (Box 3 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 29)
  - Jacob Weisberg, "This Is Your Death", 1991 July 1 (Box 3 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 30)
  - Meeting Minutes and Notes, material from Jack McCarthy, 1991 August 9 (Box 3 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 31)
  - David C. Baldus, "Death Penalty Proportionality Review Project: Final Report to the New Jersey Supreme Court" (Draft) [1 of 2], 1991 August 10 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 1)
  - David C. Baldus, "Death Penalty Proportionality Review Project: Final Report to the New Jersey Supreme Court" (Draft) [2 of 2], 1991 August 10 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 2)
  - David C. Baldus, "Death Penalty Proportionality Review Project: Final Report to the New Jersey Supreme Court" - Appendices and Tables (Draft) [1 of 2], 1991 August 10 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 3)
  - David C. Baldus, "Death Penalty Proportionality Review Project: Final Report to the New Jersey Supreme Court" - Appendices and Tables (Draft) [2 of 2], 1991 August 10 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 4)
  - David C. Baldus, "Death Penalty Proportionality Review Project: Final Report to the New Jersey Supreme Court" (Draft), 1991 August 11 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Proportionality Review, 1991 August 13; 1991 October 9 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 6)
  - Progress Report on Preliminary Case Screening, ca. 1991 August 24 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 7)
  - David Baldus, New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall: Death Penalty Proportionality Review Project, A Report to The New Jersey Supreme Court (Draft), 1991 August 27 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 8)
  - David C. Baldus, "Report to the New Jersey Supreme Court concerning State v. Marshall" (Draft), 1991 August 27 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 9)
  - David C. Baldus, "Report to the New Jersey Supreme Court concerning State v. Marshall" (Draft), 1991 August 27 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 10)
  - Memorandum from David Baldus concerning changes to the final draft of the New Jersey Proportionality Review Project, 1991 August 30 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 11)
  - Technical Appendix 10: Logistic Multiple - Regression Models and Scales, 1991 September 5 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 12)
  - David Baldus, Death Penalty Proportionality Review, 1991 September 6 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 13)
  - Corrections to database DCI, Questions for September Meeting, 1991 September 6 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 14)
  - New Jersey Court Sentencing decisions, ca. 1991 September 19 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 15)
  - David C. Baldus, "Death Penalty Proportionality Review Project Final Report to the New Jersey Supreme Court, 1991 September 24 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 16)
  - David C. Baldus, Death Penalty Proportionality Review Project - Final Report to the New Jersey Supreme Court, 1991 September 24 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 17)
  - David C. Baldus, Death Penalty Proportionality Review Project - Final Report to the New Jersey Supreme Court - Appendices and Tables [1 of 2], 1991 September 24 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 18)
  - David C. Baldus, Death Penalty Proportionality Review Project - Final Report to the New Jersey Supreme Court - Appendices and Tables [2 of 2], 1991 September 24 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 19)
  - David C. Baldus, Report to the New Jersey Supreme Court concerning New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall, 1991 September 24 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 20)
  - David C. Baldus, "Report to the New Jersey Supreme Court concerning New Jersey v. Marshall", 1991 September 24 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 21)
  - David C. Baldus, "Report to the New Jersey Supreme Court concerning State v. Marshall" (Copy for public dissemination), 1991 September 24 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 22)
  - Changes to Narrative Summaries, 1991 September 24 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 23)
  - Changes to Narrative Summaries, 1991 September 24 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 24)
  - New Jersey's Capital Sentencing System: the Statutory Aggravating and Mitigating Circumstances, 1991 September 24 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 25)
  - Statement of Director Robert T. Winter on David C. Baldus Report, 1991 September 25 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 26)
  - Mail-It: Death or CA w13 Proportionality Review and date after 1986, 1991 September 26 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 27)
  - Mail-It: Death or CA w13 Proportionality Review and date after 1989, 1991 September 26 (Box 4 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 28)
  - Notes, 1991 October 7; Undated (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Proportionality Review, 1991 October 24; 1992 February 20 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 2)
  - New Jersey v. McDougald (mental illness), 1991 October 31 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 3)
  - Data Tables and Notes, 1991 November 15; Undated (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 4)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Appendix to Brief on behalf of Defendant - Appellant volume III (Piece F), 1991 November 15 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 5)
  - Table 5: Table of Ptrail by County, 1991 November 15 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 6)
  - "Strong Republican trend registered by state's voters", 1991 November 19 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 7)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Brief of Amicus Curiae, 1991 November 26 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 8)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Brief of Amicus Curiae, 1991 November 26 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 9)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Brief of Amicus Curiae, 1991 November 26 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 10)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Brief of Amicus Curiae, 1991 November 26 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 11)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Brief and Appendix on behalf of the State of New Jersey Addressing Proportionality Review, 1991 November 26 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 12)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Brief on behalf of Defendant - Appellant Volume II (Piece D), 1991 November 26 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 13)
  - Herbert I. Weisberg, "Proportionality Review of Death Sentences in New Jersey an Independent Analysis of Data on Capital Charging and Sentencing", 1991 November 26 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 14)
  - Herbert I. Weisberg, "Proportionality Review of Death Sentences in New Jersey an Independent Analysis of Data on Capital Charging and Sentencing", 1991 November 26 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 15)
  - Herbert I. Weisberg, "Proportionality Review of Death Sentences in New Jersey", 1991 November 26 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 16)
  - Weisberg Report Memorandum, 1991 November 26 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 17)
  - Judith L. Borman, Bernadette DcCastro, Dale Jones, memorandum and discussing Weisberg Report, 1991 December 20 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 18)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Reply Brief of Amicus Curiae, 1991 December 30 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 19)
  - Draft of letter from Leigh Bienen concerning New Jersey v. Marshall and 1992 Proportionality review legislation, ca. 1992 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 20)
  - Correspondence - New Jersey v. Marko Bey, 1992 January 13; 1993 February 11 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 21)
  - Review Articles, 1992 January 21 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 22)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Weisberg Response with notes, 1992 January 29 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 23)
  - New Jersey Assembly Bills, 1992 March 17 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 24)
  - Testimony of Alexander H. Southwell before the Senate Judiciary Committee of the New Jersey Legislature concerning Proportionality Review, 1992 March 23 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 25)
  - Revised Data Collection Instrument (DCI), 1992 April 21 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 26)
  - 25th and 26th wave - list of cases with project status clearly out, 1992 April 22 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 27)
  - David C. Baldus, "The Proportionality Review of Death Sentences: New Jersey Options", 1992 April 23 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 28)
  - Correspondence - Proportionality Review, 1992 April 30; 1992 December 3 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 29)
  - New Case Summaries - No Penalty Trial Cases, 1992 June; 1992 September (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 30)
  - New Jersey v. Kevin Jackson, 1992 June 10 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 31)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Notice of Motion for Reconsideration of Proportionality Review, 1992 August 6 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1992 August 17 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 33)
  - New Jersey Public Defenders - cost and budget, 1992 August 24 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 34)
  - Boxes stored for Leigh Bienen, 1992 August 28 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 35)
  - Constitutional Amendment to Require State Funding of the Judicial System, 1992 October 21 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 36)
  - Correspondence - Claudia Van Wyt and DCI, 1992 November 12 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 37)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - transcript of A.O.C Meeting, 1992 November 13 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 38)
  - Data Tables, 1992 December 2 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 39)
  - Correspondence - Proportionality Review, 1992 December 9; 1993 February 18 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 40)
  - New Jersey v. Martini - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 41)
  - New Jersey v. John Martini - Tables of Cases and Summaries, ca. 1993 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 42)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Principal Appendix to Brief Volume I, 1993 January 28 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 43)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Principal Appendix to Brief Volume II, 1993 January 28 (Box 5 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 44)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Technical Appendix to Brief Volume I, 1993 January 28 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 1)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Technical Appendix to Brief Volume II, 1993 January 28 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 2)
  - New Jersey v. Bey - Appendices and Tables, 1993 January 28 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 3)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Appendices and Tables [1 of 2], 1993 January 28 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 4)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Appendices and Tables [2 of 2], 1993 January 28 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 5)
  - DCI Data on "Afterthought" Robbery/Murder cases, 1993 February 13 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 6)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Brief on behalf of Defendant - Appellant, ca. 1993 March (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 7)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Principle Appendix on brief on Behalf of Appellant - Defendant Volume I, ca. 1993 March (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 8)
  - New Jersey v. John Martini - Appendix to Brief Volume I, 1993 March 23 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 9)
  - Status of New Jersey Capital Cases, 1993 March 30 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 10)
  - New Jersey v. John Martini -Proportionality Review, 1993 April 27 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 11)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Brief on behalf of the Attorney General Amicus Curiae -, 1993 April 29 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 12)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Appendix on behalf of the Attorney General Amicus Curiae -, 1993 April 29 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 13)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Reply Brief on Behalf of Defendant - Appellant, 1993 May 6 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 14)
  - New Jersey Proportionality Review Data file used in New Jersey v. Martini, 1993 May 18 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 15)
  - New Jersey v. John Martini, 1993 June 2; 1993 June 14 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 16)
  - David Baldus and George Woodworth, "Proportionality: the view of the Special Master," and Herbert I. Weisberg, "Proportionality: An Alternative View." (Prepublication), 1993 June 17 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 17)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1993 June 25 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 18)
  - New Jersey v. John Martini, 1993 July (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 19)
  - New Jersey v. John Martini - Appendices and Tables [1 of 2], 1993 July 23 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 20)
  - New Jersey v. John Martini - Appendices and Tables [2 of 2], 1993 July 23 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 21)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Brief and Appendix of Amicus Curiae, 1993 September 24 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 22)
  - New Jersey v. John Martini - On Proportionality Review of a Death Sentence, 1993 September 30 (Box 6 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 23)
  - Correspondence - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall reused Appendix to Defendant's Amended Petition for Post-Conviction Relief, 1993 October; 1993 November (Box 7 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 1)
  - Report of the New Jersey Supreme Court's Ad Hoc Committee on Jury Selection in Criminal Cases, 1993 October (Box 7 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 2)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey Motion to Submit Evidence of Continuing Race Disparities, 1993 October 21 (Box 7 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 3)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall Amended Petition for Post - Conviction Relief [1 of 2], 1993 October 22 (Box 7 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 4)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall Amended Petition for Post - Conviction Relief [2 of 2], 1993 October 22 (Box 7 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 5)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall Appendix to Amended Petition for Post - Conviction Review [1 of 2], 1993 October 22 (Box 7 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 6)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall Appendix to Amended Petition for Post - Conviction Review [2 of 2], 1993 October 22 (Box 7 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 7)
  - Wave 32, Modifications to Data Collection Instrument, 1994 May 13 (Box 7 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1994 October 18 (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 1)
  - Pennsylvania Death Penalty Research - Print out of Capital cases, 1995 July 13 (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 2)
  - Memo: Prejudicial Factors Death in Sentencing, 1995 December 20 (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 3)
  - New Jersey v. Donald Coftin, 1996 November 18 (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 4)
  - Public Defender Capital Case Monthly Report, 1996 November 18 (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 5)
  - Appendix B, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 6)
  - David Baldus Survey to Attorneys of Record in Capital Cases, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 7)
  - Data Tables, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 8)
  - Data Tables - Appendix B Tables, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 9)
  - Data Tables - Background Tables, n=146, wh/non-wh, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 10)
  - Data Tables - Background not used, n=146, wh/bc/h, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 11)
  - Data Tables - not used, white/non-white, n=252, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 12)
  - Data Tables - old regressions not published with RL Ron interim reports, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 13)
  - Law and Society Paper - tables, not to publish, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 14)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey Brief on Behalf of the State of New Jersey, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 15)
  - Notes, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 16)
  - Notes on Capital Cases in other states, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 17)
  - Notes from October 29, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 18)
  - Notes on Proportionality Review, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 19)
  - References, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 20)
  - Stage Jumping Analysis, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 21)
  - Supplement to working Draft of Interim Report to the New Jersey Supreme Court - Appendix E, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 22)
  - Table I (hand written) - Distribution of cases by tear and county, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 23)
  - Table B III - Statutory Mitigating Factors, Undated (Box 8 (1-New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records), Folder 24)
- Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material, 1979-2011, Undated; 2; 7 cubic ft.
  This series documents Leigh Bienen's work as a legal scholar of the death penalty and her teaching career at Princeton University and Northwestern University. Included are records from her scholarly research on capital punishment consisting of questionnaires, case summaries, and procedural wirings. This includes the New Jersey Public Defender Homicide Study. The series also contains Bienen's publications on the death penalty, conference materials, syllabi and teaching material, and reports, legislation, and publications used directly in her research.
  - Research on Capital Punishment cost, 1983; 1987; 1988 (Box 1 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 1)
  - Literature on Determinate Sentencing in Illinois with annotations, 1984; 1993; 2004; 2009; 2010 (Box 1 (2-Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material), Folder 2)